welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
boom alright check-ins I'm absolutely
exhausted but I feel nice
now just like plugging with Jason and
Jared I was like seeing those guys so
welcome to the stoah I am the Stewart of
the stoah and so is a place for us to
cohere and dialogue but what matters
most at the nice edge rates of this
moment so if you co a sheep with a new
motto we just chop things so for the new
faces here what we're having we're
having weekly sessions or maybe we're
having weekly sessions called the
mediation campfire and this concept that
this idea emerged from a conversation
that Jared and Jason and myself did on
the stove podcast about having sort of
around this digital campfire just
spitballing how do what is mathematic
mediation and how to make it happen in
the noosphere so this is sort of like
high-level discussion just this like
just FYI there's a lot of insider
baseball stuff that may happen here but
we thought this might be the best way to
kind of evolve the discussion because
both Jason and myself just submitted
articles on mimetic mediation to the
side view so this is sort of a merging
topic and immersion conversation but the
three of us really believe that it's
needed and Jason and Jared they have a
podcast called both end and it's it's
maybe it's the official unofficial frame
of being a memetic mediation podcast or
that's one of the explicit themes so how
today is gonna work is that three of us
are just gonna jam for me with like 5-10
minutes about from the mediation maybe
stuff that we talked about last time and
we're gonna open it up to the group
we're gonna have a group discussion and
see where it flows so that being said to
adjacent you want to start off with
initial thoughts sure well I feel like
maybe we should introduce the concept a
little bit just because there are a lot
of new faces here and so for those that
don't know that the concept actually
came I think he was coined by by Peter
he's being humble but it was coined by
him
and in a paper with Connor Barnes coach
42.0 and basically the premise and
correct me if I'm wrong Peter was that
we have we're witnessing kind of a
fractionating set of what are called
nomadic tribes or what he called mimetic
tribes and due to the nature of the
internet and perhaps algorithms and
things of that nature there's this kind
of filter bubbles or reality tunnels
better forming and you know they're
internally coherent give or take but
they they tend to strawman outside
groups and they tend to just think that
they have the correct mu on reality
right and and I guess coming at it from
my point of view you know and why I
resonated with that term and and we
started talking about it is that for me
you know we with the rise of the
internet there's a great opportunity to
you know have some kind of collective
sense making that might be some kind of
alternative to the current current
institutions in society
but in order for that to happen there
needs to be some kind of robust
information flow across all of these
different communities so that they can
coordinate not that they need to like
each other necessarily but there needs
to be some kind of common language or
you know some kind of common translation
so at least you know we're not straw
Manning each other and you know we're
collaborating when possible and so
that's basically how I understand the
premise and it's an open source concept
it hasn't really been you know put down
into a set of formal heuristics or
workshops but it's something that Jared
and I've you know we've had this podcast
for about a year and we try and just
bring on people from many different
perspectives on to the podcast and just
have a constructive conversation you
know so it's not nothing really new or
you know it's nothing that none of us
are familiar with but it's I guess it's
particularly meant for the online space
although it doesn't have to be in the
online space but it's it's just trying
to have a better
collective dialogue I'll leave it that
or no Peter Jared want to add anything
jump injured nothing nothing at the
moment still kind of in a very open
space right now yeah I think that's a
good good description or a good good
foundation to delay at least actually
one thing I will say if you didn't if
anybody didn't get a chance to watch
this this conversation that we had last
week one of the common themes was around
seeing or at least from our perspective
it seems like we see the thematic
mediation as a longer term goal or
orientation as opposed to some sort of
like you know seeking you know some sort
of consensus reality in in in single
sittings or something like that so yeah
I think this is this is more of like a
process orientation rather than some
sort of short-term outcome oriented
project and I think that that kind of
shifts the frame a bit and allows us to
be a little bit to occupy the kind of
space in between as opposed to you know
go hearing some specific pneumatic mmm
medic mediation tribe or something like
that so yeah just just to add a bit a
bit there so that we don't get on that
rabbit hole again because I know we've
been on it many times so it's a common
common perspective yeah and so the last
week there was that kind of like a
debate between should we have a
superordinate goal that unites all the
tribes together and we have to get
people rallying around that or sort of
like you know Jason's metaphor just
everyone grab a beer around the digital
campfire feel the warmth together and
feel each other's heart that's step one
and then we can start talking you know
business propositional business and
what's merging of those stoah so what's
happening in my mind with this this
mimetic tribal term like asymmetrical
communication if you just start talk
about propositions and strange
attractors on asymmetrical communication
platforms like Twitter or Facebook
you're gonna create mimetic tribes
because there's like a disembodied
component to it but what I like about
this space of the stoah is
there's like an embodied energy
happening like like existential dance
party were dancing together we're
feeling the same things yesterday a
Tyson who's in the room right now he did
this freestyling through the pandemic
which is all this flow state I felt
deeply connected ray is doing the
snapping of fingers it just felt like
the energy was there the love was there
and so I think there's something there
to make that transition between the
mimetic tribe to the embody tribe and
there has to be a more emphasis on
community however that community gets
formed over broadcasts over the
broadcast medium yeah I well I couldn't
agree more with this is one thing that I
recently wrote about is that you know
and this is really just really basic and
old-school but I think you know before
any of us you know if we have
disagreements in terms of ideology
worldview things like that I mean it's
so much easier to connect sub
ideological you know and just as you
know Peter said get a get a beer around
the campfire or you know share it share
a love for a similar you know musical
form or some other aesthetic you know
play sports you know all of these things
are just kind of like old school but you
know it's it's really you know it feels
like and that's what that's why the
internet is so you know it's such a
difficult medium sometimes for you know
or why the Internet can promote discord
is because we're not having these
embodied relational experiences right
and so I think what you're doing Peter
with this dough and these more embody
things even though it's still you know
remote over video is that you know we
are developing more of these relational
bonds and then when we do get to like
okay like the way you see the world is
stupid and I'm gonna tell you why like
when you start having that conversation
or at least menteur maybe a little bit
less you know confrontational you know
there's a little bit more shared empathy
and and relational trust built that you
could actually you know have a more good
good-faith conversation yeah and I would
also kind of add there to Peter I've
seen
this is embodied component I think the
reason it's so important kind of
doubling down on this these the the
things that kind of hold the tribes
together are very cognitive and
intellectual and and you know they doing
things like that you're a little state
checks or whatever you do whenever you
open these sessions beater of kind of
getting into your body and being aware
of your emotional relevance and
displaying it to everybody kind of being
vulnerable with that it was such a human
thing that it's a great way to
immediately realize that you were in in
dialog with with other humans and and
we're not here to you know just simply
live in the Met mimetic Wars I suppose
right and I think I mentioned this last
time I did like that emotional check-ins
with Jack Murphy and I mentioned I was
nervous or whatever and then and invited
him I think to mention he was nervous
he's like you know uber alpha male
mastery guy so I think yeah just being
in that presence like modeling that I
think it's helpful this is the last
thing I'll say and then maybe one more
round open up to the group but one thing
I thought might be interesting is to
actually explore ideas of how we can
maybe seduce people into this digital
campfire that have different ideological
opinions just to get them to deal with
each other in a way and I'll share an
idea that Jordan Hall sent me via email
the other day
so basically created a weekly new show
that provides local weather medical aid
weather reports in a way from earnest
members of different cultural tribes
like Pat Ryan give some people a chance
BJ can will get something from the gun
culture somebody from SJW land and I
think with my kind of ability to be a
performative agnostic and then this kind
of space being as open as it is I think
this could be a good place for something
like that so I thought that was a really
cool idea and anyone wants to take the
lead on that let me know but I imagine
there's other ideas that could emerge
with that spirit so I'm curious with you
and Jason and Jared think about that
I like the idea and I might actually
really like to open it up to others soon
to see what everyone else thinks I mean
we need you know volunteers to you know
like we would need like you said seduce
like the people reporting on okay this
is this this kind of loosely knit
subgroup of people that you know have a
you know somewhat of a coherent
worldview at least implied they would
have to kind of be a trusted member in
that group right because you know if we
start having Outsiders come in and give
reports you know and if it's slanted it
might you know turn I don't know like it
just it just might not go over well
right if members of that group that are
being reported on be like who is this
guy like we don't know this guy like he
doesn't know anything like his bias is
honestly of no way you know so that's
there's just that but I'm really curious
to open it up to others and see see what
others think at this point go from there
cool cool so if you know I trust the
discernment of everyone in the group so
if anyone feels like they want to come
off mute and just chat about anything
that's been said we'll just your popcorn
style and see what emerges who is the
first piece of corn that wants to pop
them one is like it sounds like instead
of coming up with like a sort of a
central goal of what you're working on I
mean they're at least part of it is like
how do you sit with multiple reality you
know like holding space for multiple
realities at the same time so there's
the cultivation of that skill which I
don't know whether it be a goal in and
of itself but that's one piece and then
the other thing that came up is I'm I
just noticed a contraction in my system
we use the word seduce that and I come
from I spent a lot of time in the
12-step world and one of the things that
we have is this concept of Attraction
rather than promotion how do you attract
how do you make what you're doing more
attractive that instead of trying to
promote it or yeah there's something
about that that word seduce that I was
like I don't I'm
a fan of that that that but but I do
understand the concept from you know
it's like you don't want to promote it
but at the same time how do i how do we
get more people to participate in I do
like the idea of a weather report all
pop so cure one phrase you mentioned was
like being able to hold multiple
perspectives or ideas and I've to meet
there are two creators that have good
examples of like having they won't
create or have different discussions
like with themselves as different people
so contra points if you all know her she
has a couple of videos where she has
like three or four different
personalities there's like cat girl left
and I'm like neo like centrist left girl
like debating or something and then Jay
reg also his is a bit kind of character
like but it's kind of kind of
entertaining he where he has all these
different he uses the like the political
the to a political spectrum and that has
characters that sort of exists in each
part of the spectrum so at least from an
entertainment perspective those could be
two sources of ideas or inspiration yeah
the thing that's coming up on that is
the it seems to be two different
orientations and one of them both of
them I think are super valuable I know
Peter likes the phrase performative
agnostic which seems to be kind of like
throwing yourself in embodying a certain
perspective and feeling what it feels
like to be coming from that orientation
which is very kind of like I guess it's
primarily embodied a technique and then
the other one would be kind of trying to
occupy the space that surrounds
each of the each of the different
perspectives
I think the especially the performative
agnostic the kind of embodied
orientation seems to be a very direct
route to kind of pulling out you're
pulling on certain triggers and and
themes that you you might be might be
less or more sensitive in so it feels
like a little bit more direct route but
yeah I don't know I me personally I
think I usually end up being a little
bit more in the empty space around
around things but possibly because I
spend a lot of time kind of in my own
ideological tribes and deeply embodied
for quite some years and took a while to
crawl myself out so yeah just some some
random thoughts to throw in there I'm
really I think I'm really curious if if
anybody wants to share in their own you
know life or mimetic space if there's
you know if there's certain kind of you
know worldviews that are that are kind
of in tension with each other even
within yourself right because once that
one thing that I don't know the way I
think of it often times is that you know
we're trying to mediate tribes in the
outside world because there's there's
there's warring tribes within us right
and there's warring ideas within us and
memes and worldviews that create some
kind of cognitive dissonance and so I'm
curious if anybody would like to share
you know within your own you know in
your own sphere what some of those
dissonant you know mental models are
either that you observe but you'reyou're
kind of participated in or it's just
barely really internal yeah anybody
would like to share that I'll share and
sorry I think I'm just a number and no
face I don't know how to change I won
one that I've observed recently is this
cognitive dissonance between
I guess kind of like wanting to be pro
like in on the progressive side of
things wanting to be pro restorative
justice or pro like anti mass
incarceration and I'm Pro forgiveness or
pro not judging people by the worst
thing they ever did but then on the
other side
not wanting to lend that to people who
commit sexual abuse of power it's like
how on the one hand can I be pro
forgiveness while being pro zero
tolerance for perpetrators of sexual
abuse it's something I've kind of come
up against a little bit in my work is
that cognitive dissonance but that is
something I've I've witnessed and then I
just wanted to throw in a response to
the previous question of what kind of
our kind of the previous topic of what
kind of tactics might might help
facilitate mimetic mediation I have I
have this little I guess I it's a it's a
practice that I developed and I also
just have to say as someone who has
attempted to facilitate conversation and
interaction between different worldviews
it's really hard to get like certain
worldviews are in and of themselves not
particularly interested in interacting
with other worldviews like that is that
is of interest to some mimetic tribes
and not others right liberal literally
means open and that is a value that some
mimetic tribes have I didn't I didn't I
mean I think that could be an
interesting I'm like meta column in the
you know mimetic tribe spreadsheet is
like how interested are you or open are
you to even kind of engaging with and
acknowledging the other tribes are even
acknowledging that you're like one of
many tribes but anyway the technique is
um I call it where I'm coming from and
what I have done and I'll just give a
specific example so I did this at
Facebook with them Facebook employees
and then like non non Facebook employees
who were there for a an event but
and I have people do a little bit of
guided writing about in this case it was
like it's just how hot like how we feel
about Facebook our hopes and fears about
Facebook and then people put all of
their writings in a pile at the front of
the room and then people come up one by
one pull out up pull out a testimonial
and read it out loud
in first person as if it was their own
and it's just a very simple way of
inhabiting where someone else is coming
from and and off it's kind of disarming
because often it's really obvious that
someone is reading something that they
don't agree with but there's really
nothing else to do other than just kind
of like speak another person's
perspective in first person and just get
inside of it and see where that takes
you and it actually it kind of just
brought some humor into the space which
was really helpful for them getting down
and dirty and having a conversation
between Facebook employees and like I
don't need to go into the specifics of
what the event was that it just kind of
injected some honesty and humor into the
room so that we could actually just kind
of like have a real I guess you could
say kind of somewhat mimetic mediated
conversation included a list of
conversational modalities every street
partland
I and John rebecky kind of are
collecting so if you have any one you
add there and some of these I think
could be used for you know various
emetic mediation exercises maybe I think
on that last note that was just
mentioned that there's medic tried I
don't even want up and each other ones
so I think that that's one I belong to
generally where there's very little
interest and even like really perceiving
an external world use in an active
fashion and then things trickle in but
no one's really interested I am in
Orthodox trip in Israel background
there's not only so much interest
there's not extreme antagonism usually
also just kind of like this indifference
but the girls will be antagonism
revelation to some extent and that's why
I kind of actually go back to Peter
saying seduce I felt like that is kind
of a way where it's almost I want to say
trickery but something else was a
session last last week where you take a
bunch of people and say let's get
together and talk about our ideas our
different ideologies so you're doing the
very strong selection bias there like
you're only going to get the people who
are actually open and interested a
certain extent we're seeking that but if
you kind of do oh we're doing this rough
work session and through that you're
kind of creating these personal
connections that you guys are talking
about that could be like a starting
platform I feel for onward I feel like
that there might me to if you want to
really get like the heavy the heavy
hitters you might have to kind of trick
them to create personal connections
around something different otherwise
you're kind of treading water getting
the guys were already kind of open for
ends anyway or appeal to them using
their their Telos or you know their goal
their intention and and and ideally kind
of like create something for them that
you know appeals to what they're seeking
yeah it's funny this uh the image of the
Trojan horse seems to be very alive in
my experience right now and they're you
know I think I've seen a number of
different instances where people are
kind of seduced one of them is kind of
the the back door of like you know
presenting it as one thing when it's
actually something else so this would be
the you know the stoic breath or
something like that and you're just
setting up circumstances where people
have to be in dialogue or in in relation
with people that they normally wouldn't
be with and it's a very soft approach
and one that I think is you know kind of
essential it has to be part of the group
anyway and then there's another one
that's let me be a little bit more
manipulative but also still has is still
truthful in its own way and I think
could possibly be valuable with some of
the most combative tribes and that is
just this that you know your enemy
meme I know a lot of
I've heard a lot of stories of people
being kind of stuck in one area or one
ideological perspective with a clear
idea of who their enemy is and wanting
to figure out how to defeat them and so
they kind of expose themselves
deliberately to their enemy to
understand them and then kind of come
out the other end realizing that maybe
there's a lot of assumptions that were
being made that they didn't quite
understand you know there's a very
provocative story of a a black jazz
player who befriended a bunch of KKK
members and converting a bunch of them
just because his curiosity of not
understanding where they're coming from
and wanting to understand why they hated
him and yeah I don't know I'm sure
there's some other Trojan horses that we
could think of here - yeah just some
class Sam Jason oh I don't want to cut
off this conversation we're just going
to say that
Rasmus who's not sure that the internet
will allow him to speak had it had a
number of observations and I was gonna I
was gonna read those but I don't want to
cut off the the train if this is you
want to take go ahead you know for it
okay so so this from Rasmus unless he
wants to try and speak now I don't want
to steal his words I'd like to try but
okay like so Jamie okay thank you
and yesterday the basic idea here is
just to to have a prior knowledge and
before we engage in a conversation and
so there's three major areas where this
panelist could be so yeah like the first
sorta forum so
and survivor this is depending for some
time so it is same on a what's the video
for you last week and work on this
specifically for today so how it fits in
Soho
so the first thing is what kind of forum
so what is the aim to goal so do we need
to arrive and something or just discuss
or then I'm also the yes I have
knowledge
about how different truth processes
works and so is some kind of agreement
about that and then also like your own
contribution and many of these things is
not something you can just like we and
then no like you have to embody them
like you also say so and yeah like so
not of learning in doing this but I'm
just but for me about mediation it's
just that if you can have this chat then
yeah you can also and then you it's
rational it's sensible it's made for
some project that as Aaron can hopefully
agree on is is for the better good for
the better conversation and yeah you can
be held to this standard so that as a
standard that can hold you yes so a
couple of fragments are coming up so I
like that sort of a training program of
medic mediation like maybe one step is
to what was tracked what Connor and I
track on that spreadsheet just
propositional levels what they believed
to be true so you can pass their
ideological tutoring test and maybe
other step is to method act their
reality tunnel so what do they feel when
they believe what they believe right
like what do they feel in their body and
then like have the capacity to process
their I'm in the position I feel quite
strongly about this that you can't
really speak with anyone unless you know
what they're feeling right if you feel
their emotional reality because you're
just gonna misstep and say the wrong
thing it's like I I like to have you
have maybe a training program emerging
in a previous fragment that came up is
kind of like the battlefronts of the
culture were like what are the hot spots
right now and maybe have a spreadsheet
that like tracks that or some way to
track that so like a real I'll mention
one that I'm concerned with right now
but one that I'm not too concerned with
but it's a battlefront is trans medical
astray ins trenders I don't know if
anyone is familiar with that so in like
the trans community there's
people who think that you're only could
be transgendered if you have gender
dysmorphia and then if you don't have
that then you're just a transgender and
then they have like war between each
other then contra points got involved in
that I think she got sucked up in that
little war
that's a battlefront and maybe someone's
called to mediate between that so that
could be a thing battlefront that I'm
concerned about is the conspiracy theory
battlefront with Q and on and then how
that's fractionating I was talking to
fuller David fuller from rebel wisdom
about this yesterday and it looks like a
demon is being born through this kind of
like collective dialogue and the
trumpets movement is is associating with
it as well and there's a lot of
intelligent people in that community
plugged into it so it'd be interesting
to have conversations there but yeah I
like the idea that there's some kind of
like tracking system with all this and
then see whose call to mediate it like
maybe people who can speak to both in
such a way and the last thing I'll say
is that I wrote this article with David
Cosley called marginal figures and this
came up when Ben was talking about like
marginal figures someone who has your
foot in the tribe and the foot outside
of it but they're really respected by
the tribe that they belong to and then
you kinda remind me of that like you
seem like a marginal figure in your
tribe because you're plugged in you're
you know but I think there is characters
who can speak to their own tribe and
then can speak outside of it too and
those are the kind of the figures that
we got to like find and then get them in
this digital campfire well people who
have gone from one tribe to another
yeah bridge people exactly right my self
not a faceless number that tells the
story of people who have shifted their
political worldviews transcended
extremism made all kinds of
transformative change those people are
bridge people so yeah people who have
shifted from one tribe to another can
speak to the tribe they came from and to
the tribe they came to and obviously
have the kind
like meta just kind of like
understanding of tribes existing period
so yeah those are very valuable voices
cheer I would say I don't want to use
topic radically I think this is
continuation I feel intuitively although
I don't know exactly um just an
experience that I had this week that I'm
very much wanted that kind of presents
just to hear it also people's opinions
this week I accidentally stumbled across
a website called um I think it was the
internet into Intifada which is a very
strong for Palestinian website and I'm
not like a strong ideologist I'm so
aware of the far before that is sort I
don't have a strong opinion anything on
the Israeli passing in conflict or just
being and seeing the things from the
other perspective and seeing things
radically different mins shock my system
in a body way things I knew
intellectually experienced otherwise but
one thing that struck me very strongly
and connecting to the mimetic mediation
is that I felt like the argument on all
sides almost oil down to the facts in
the sense that every side if they were
charged like no we don't do that if we
did do that we'd be terrible people but
we don't do that where that was kind of
the perspective everything and I was
kind of thinking about a memetic
mediation in general we have people with
these um so strong strongly different
values or maybe it's not really
difference in values maybes difference
of interpretation of objective facts and
maybe they can kind of connect like we
all want social justice right we all
want people to be treated equally and
nicely and humanely well what that means
because of the facts a little bit
different I wonder how that could kind
of flow in
what popped into my head been fun as you
we're talking about that is something
from Virgil a coffee and she wrote
something that this was more in terms of
the larger conservative versus liberal
idea but the idea of the underlying
metaphorical models that each side had
and it was a difference not invalid it
wasn't a different and difference in
values but a difference in ordering of
the values they had the same values they
just ordered them slightly different and
that slight difference what was big you
know made a huge difference and I I'm
trying to think of off the top of my
head I mean it's like they both valued
love but how they expressed that love
was or yeah compassion like for the
conservative it was more of the strict
father type of compassion whereas for
liberals it was more of like the you
know compassionate mother type of
underlying models that's what that's
what I thought of as we were talking
about that because it's the thing that's
so interesting is that the differences
are slight I mean it's it's the ordering
of values it's not that the values are
very different it's just the order that
we that people put them in and how do
you how do you bring that to the surface
that's really really good what's coming
to mind the term a protein a
superordinate goal so the superordinate
goal always shifts depending on what
kind of the conversation you want to
emerge and when you were talking what
came to mind is that I had this event in
person lined up supposed to be about
mate but Cove it happened and it was
extinction rebellion the representatives
of extinction rebellions in Toronto
talking with the effect of altruist
community because they have a similar
super ordinate goal they want to save
the world you know respond to the medic
Rice's but the responses are radically
different and just having them together
to chat would be nice build some bridges
there maybe I'll do it online and stow
it now but I like that idea of if it
kind of sniffing out those battlefronts
and then saying
what is the the framing that they're
gonna track both of them to get to the
the campfire what's coming to mind right
now is is like what you know for for
kind of self-styled medic mediators what
does it mean to be a trustworthy person
who can build trust in certain
communities as somebody that you're
still maybe you're not even a marginal
figure you're just they'll tolerate you
you know being part of their
conversational space because you're not
attacking them and you know and you're
friendly with them and but you're a
person that you know they they come to
rely on to one translate ideas and memes
from other tribes from the outside world
but they also see you as an asset in a
way that well you know maybe they will
represent our worldview sympathetically
to the outside world and so as a
mediator you know one thing you know
like you know that I think about is okay
which which tribes do I feel even
remotely qualified to even build trust
within because I don't think any of us
can cover the whole range right we you
know with limited time energy and we
just you know like our life experience
precludes us from I think sympathizing
with everything right unless we're just
completely Zen about everything and we
actually don't really understand it
we're just you know we're not actually
getting into the meat of it we're just
you know floating around sorry dude
attack on you maybe it was anyway so
yeah this is more of like a an inquiry
prompt of like you know we think about
okay which groups can we build
relationships with a couple people one
or two people in the group you know in
order to when things flare up you know
you're you you know because if there's
no if there's no battle line if they're
just different worldviews and they're
coexisting peacefully then well you know
I mean it's not really a big deal if
they're if they're pretty separated but
when things flare up all of a sudden you
know like you're well positioned to to
be a mediator to translate you know
intentions and goals and values and
facts and everything else among these
groups yeah it'd be a bit of a
contrarian here and I guess kind of on
this broader theme I think that
mediation the first kind of connotation
with mediation is is this kind of
peacekeeping effort of you know meeting
when mediation is needed and it's
obvious and I think I actually have my
intuition well I think both it's true in
many ways I also think it's more of a
kind of like a last-ditch effort in the
sense that most of the most effective
mediation that I see is happening when
the mediation isn't known about so it's
kind of like very Taoist in the sense of
like the best leaders the ones that
don't nobody knows they're leading and
you know so so so a lot of times that
might look like so we've brought up a
couple of her things like one of them is
like if there's just fundamental
disagreements on what is true I I'm very
skeptical of of making any kind of
conflict you know conflicting and
investigation into breaking down
barriers and actually I think in a lot
of cases it actually just makes them
stronger and what what tends to be the
most interesting for me and I think
Jason and I do is a lot on both hand is
to have people on the podcast who have
strong beliefs and take a genuine
interest obviously I think this is the
core here we have no agenda
but kind of exploring the boundaries of
those beliefs and trying to maybe kind
of loosen them a little bit play with
you know where there's some paradoxes
might come up with where some
uncertainty starts to be engaged and and
you know sparking maybe some curiosity
of what's beyond those boundaries or how
somebody else might see it differently
so yeah I guess the the the provocative
claim here is that I think most of the
effective mediation that I feel
happening when it's happening is when
there's it's not seen as mediation it's
just a CO exploration and relational
kind of dialogue or interaction and I
mean it doesn't even have to be dialogue
you know I think
you know to get into our body embodied
space I've definitely danced with people
where they got to push me out of my you
know my preconceived notions of what
dancing is or something like that right
like that this is something that that is
unfolding on many different levels and
really it's kind of relationally pushing
the boundaries of kind of concrete ideas
of where where things ended began yeah
something throw out there jump in here
and say wow you guys
before I lose myself completely I just
want to get under the floor but I love
the idea of the weather reports but
perhaps speaking speaking from that
place but rather than for it but
speaking for yourself and so that the
transparency of your your own inquiry
could be there and jeredy like what
you're saying just let me be about that
not going directly for it but indirectly
and even to really follow that to the
extreme if you did something like action
learning and really support people from
one of those tribes to have with a
problem to voice that problem to mask
clarifying questions about it and and
then to to look to add resources and
support for that for that to happen to
make it a really safe place but the
space would be a lot connected er and
safer when we speak you know our own
truth with the weather reports and
really make that safe and Invitational
for people to do it rather than having
them sort of labeled with their their
tribe and I loved it with the writing
exercise that's definitely started off
like big that's fantastic and it would
really be good
you
Tyson did you have something you'd like
to say I think so I'm interested in sort
of invoking a conflict that I
experienced and then seeing what happens
from that for me
I allowed of people that I am either
friends with or just acquaintances or
friends of friends on Facebook all right
like a lot of their biggest concerns
revolve around like max vaccinations and
5g and so there are like essence there's
there's some of it which just seems like
a lot of sensational conspiracy theories
and there's other things that also scare
me quite a lot and then I also I feel
like I'm coming from a tribe that would
have like their their forebears would be
like Eckart Tolle and other spiritual
teachers and I'm coming more and then
also they're very much about like get
out of your head and into your body like
out of your head out of your head it's
like to be in your head into think is
like that's almost like the sin and so
I'd really like to use my mind and and
to think and be in conversations like
this so this is a tribe that I've been
attracted to and so and then a lot of
people that I see that are thinking very
thoughtfully and that I see is being
very intelligent and smart are very
strong against anti-vaxxers so like sam
harris is an example of someone i think
is a brilliant mind he's very thoughtful
about things and he talks about being an
anti-vaxxers like this horrible person
or something and so that and so but like
max vaccinations scare me quite a lot
but I also I would be very interested in
like hearing from somebody that is much
more equipped than me an expert in
vaccinations and how they're done and
why they can be done safely and how they
can be done safely and how we could have
vaccinations with that and not have to
have the fear um and I yeah so that's
something that when I think about it I
almost want to like kind of hide from it
because it it does that conversation
scares me and I also fear like
disconnection from some of my friends
people that I care about my relationship
with them and so I see how some
that conversation as well for them would
be difficult to have in a like a
grounded space you're not trying to I
would think of that using like the max
back kind of thing is that some that I
understand my space and also in the end
I've acts I have been derided accent so
we get his paradox where I think this is
also true anybody who is informed is own
pretty much informed because they're a
strong proponent of one side like if
anybody that really knows their stuff
it's not they came in knowing their
stuff became with the strong opinion and
that's how Andy kept that amassing the
information that sustains them and they
don't even have people who are really
kind of like you and I also say many
things like agnostic like I just want to
know you can't do the food you can't
trust the experts even because basically
they started in that direction anyway
I'm just adding to your IRA you should
and I will just just say here to you
this is these these groups out so I have
some some conspiracy folks in my family
and stuff like that and and yeah I think
that every time somebody else in the
family tries to disprove them or argue
with them it just is always a disaster
and and this is would be you know so
we've kind of talked about two things
one of them one of them being that
genetic mediators really benefit from
having frightened previous tribal
experience so that they can relate
increase and rapport with the people and
some trusts to explore but I think
there's also an equally interesting role
which is the the curious ignorant
perspective and but it has to be true
like right you can't be like I'm gonna
you can't be the socratic I'm gonna ask
you questions until you look stupid
it has to be like a genuine exploration
of the boundaries from somebody who
doesn't know anything and if you if
you're able to dialogue long enough
you'll always end up at I don't know and
if a conversation ends with an ideologue
with and I don't know I feel like that's
always some mediation has happened to
there it's kind of loosened loosen the
grip of it
Jason yet something say I mean a very
like quarterly formed thought so let's
see well I was just thinking how you
know we're all very I think you know
multifaceted not just in this group but
everyone and if we do have some kind of
coherent worldview it's kind of a
composite board of many different
influences that we kind of figured out
how to stitch together and well you were
saying Jared about you know just just
simply inquiring in good faith and you
know not not trying to prove anything
but just you're building up some kind of
rapport and and and that might not lead
anywhere on that particular issue but
just building up that rapport with that
person on some other issue you know all
of a sudden you have some trust built
that you know perhaps some mediation can
happen you know down the line right and
so again I'm going back to the notion of
embodiment and relationship you know I
really think that's that's really you
know the driver of memetic mediation is
is just good old fashioned relationship
building finding some area where you can
connect you know and it's almost
impossible not to find some area that
you can connect with somebody right and
starting starting from that foundation
and then you know when you start getting
into the more sensitive issues you have
a little bit more affordance do that
without everyone just shutting down
immediately
well in to add to that I know Jason you
like to talk a lot about how the
mediation is kind of a spiritual
practice as well and and I think the
spiritual component comes in here about
when it comes to in these in these these
attempts to have relational dialogues
with somebody that you might have a
bunch of familiarity with if we're
metacognitively aware of when some sort
of emotional strong emotional reaction
comes up that is you know that's a
practice of its own in its own is
showing you that there is some sort of
preconception or solid idea about this
topic that then can be kind of explored
and and the tricky thing here too and it
can be hard sometimes to do it while
you're in the conversation but I think
it's always really important to after
you've kind of come out of something if
you felt like you came out triggered to
then just get back into your body and
feel what with where that triggering is
you know maybe it's my shoulders are
super tense or feeling anger or you know
that they may have like however it
presents like exploring that in a
curious way as opposed to some sort of
resistant way is what because is it
actually loosening it and and you know
counter-intuitively you know like when
we see how much that emotional resonance
is kind of what is creating the barriers
and boundaries then we know that the way
to deconstruct them is also to get into
our bodies as well and kind of explore
that the sensations and in the more we
do it too the more you start to see that
these solid ideas that feel solid in our
body as well if you look closely you see
there's some kind of movement there kind
of exploring the boundaries and stuff
like that it's surprising how much this
actually affects our cognition but it's
definitely a spiritual practice you know
this is a lot of what meditation is all
about yeah mediators also need to be
mediated right I think we could be Pro
mediators in some domains and complete
you know you know culture warriors and
other domains you know I I definitely
you know still do my share of of warring
on the Internet's and you know I rely on
my budge to point out my blind spots
right and the reason I I think it's a
spiritual practice is you know it does
require humility and you know like as
we're mediating we're also being
mediated even if it's not by somebody
else like we're also have to go in with
the spirit of learning because we might
have blind spots right and as we're
trying to mediate somebody else we might
also you know get triggered and then we
have to emotionally process that and you
know our sense of identity that's
attached to a worldview has to get
loosened and that's you know to me
that's spirituality 101 right is you
know your sense of identity keeps
getting bigger and expanding and or you
know depending on how you want to phrase
it but it's you know it's it takes less
solid forms right it's more
it's more nebulous I guess you could say
more non-dual right I feel called to say
something is that the nice edge of my
thinking and then I'll stop talking and
then close up I like this idea of really
like seeing like the logical end and
emotional end or the conclusion of them
that have tribe and going there and
going all the way with it and that's how
I'll tell you one one thing that
happened to me when I research these
tribes I try to feel them too and so
when I was researching all these
conspiracy theory tribes you know like
fired up the tor browser and just
started reading like this like non-stop
reading about all this type of stuff and
I'm not gonna talk about the accuracy
because I do think there's signal to
some of that I think a lot of us noise
though but just the spirit the essence
of it cuz when you read that you become
radically paranoid you can't trust
anyone can't trust any of your loved
ones you can't even trust yourself I
remember a thought according my mind my
and my and killed her agent feels like
you just come radically paranoid and
then that's an opportunity to build a
state a relationship with that state of
radical paranoia at the end of the nice
edge of my thinking I'm thinking that
the Depok that conspiracy theory energy
is like the death of communitas for a
collective and yeah I'll just let that
sit for a moment and see if anybody has
anything to say
things come to mind I last year went
into a foray down into the Chan's and
like yeah I had that same experience of
the paranoia and go and and being
introduced to like oh my god these are
like there were things that came up and
I was like okay I need to slowly back
away from this and get right get in
relationship with myself and so yeah
there I like that framing of being able
to be in relationship to that paranoia
because how can you converse with
somebody if you can't understand the
feeling of where they're coming from and
the other thing is I clicked a glance at
the document that you put out Peter of
and the term connection Jim's and this
thought that has my husband and I have
had this thing of like it's an emotional
dojo of being able to do you know like I
my my biggest fear is getting people is
someone getting angry at me I won't
necessarily like like I could prop there
are probably situations where I could
push a little bit harder but I'm too but
I'm scared of the response and so a
situation in which like that could be
like tested and try and practice I would
like there's this part of me that's like
you know wanting to figure out how can I
make something like that come to
fruition as being able to practice that
because being able to yeah beyond that
knife's edge of like okay Ken how far
can i push before it pushed somebody too
hard I mean and they were coil but
without like getting intimidated talked
out of it by my own
you know fear of other people's anger so
something yeah I'd love to see something
like that and my minds kind of working
on how can I do I have the courage to do
something to try and set something like
that up
I have a desire to double click on your
daemon kara and so I had a similar
thought so this what's what's emerging
of the stores gonna be like a wisdom gym
I imagine where we can practice all
these things and I don't have anyone
heard about emotional effective patterns
it's an acting technique in order not to
get trauma when you when you do method
acting an actual acting technique you
can do breathing patterns where you hold
yourself in a certain way and then if
you breathe in that way reliably you
engender certain emotional state and so
like if you want joy you kind of like
close your eyes you have a smile and you
have a cascaded breathing through your
nostrils and you do that then just joy
just arts bubbling up and then you can
build a relationship with that you know
that with fear you know that with anger
and it's a sort of primordial fear
primordial anger and hatred I imagine as
well so would be really cool having a
motion gym where you do that build a
relationship with it and be friends with
it and see what may be a thoughts
emerged when they come up emotional
affective patterns I'll write it in in
the chat box in the moment but we should
close out I'm just want to open up the
floor for anyone who has any who hasn't
spoken I'm looking at David might
metagaming friend but anybody who has
any thoughts they would want to share it
hasn't spoken before we close I just
wanted to briefly comment that Peter I
love your your your strategy of like
reading the conspiracy things and seeing
what it's like to be that I love that
that's like one of my favorite things is
like I call it like gonzo anthropology
it's like you're doing anthropology but
you're like putting the like putting and
projecting the state of other people
unto yourself so for like the last like
I don't know eight months or something
I've been suffering from Twitter brain
just from like seeing what it's like
just and like besides a shortened
attention there's like I've been all
these other sort of things that that
play come at play and I'm still like
trying to put them into words but if you
have the wherewithal to sort of
experiment with different news sources
and all that that suggests you know
trying to immerse yourself in different
these different millou's and mimetic
tribes I just put some in a chat box
loop near ours off and I had an exchange
of a pair of politics conspiracy
theories and Robert Anton Wilson called
it guerrilla ontology which is a similar
to that gonzo anthropology that you were
talking about and that's sort of like
really method acting a reality tunnel so
that being said let's close out I just
maybe hand it over to Jason and Jared if
you guys have any final thoughts before
we say goodbye I guess my only final
thought is if folks are interested we do
have a slack group a medic mediation
slack group where you know it gets
sometimes it's more active sometimes
it's less active you know people get
busy but you know we kind of discussed
various topics and strategies for
mediation but also you know sometimes we
we have our own little inside Wars I
guess you could say which are always fun
and it's a good kind of little training
ground so if people are just and that
may be Peter I don't know if you want to
put the link in the chat box as well
and so you know so it's a way to kind of
keep the conversation going
well you know I think obviously video is
a better format like I vastly prefer
this than than chatting but that that's
kind of a might be an in-between you
know
Brij oh yeah I have so many there's so
many directions I that were coming up as
we were talking that I could have gone
down so I'm just wrapping fire say a
couple and Kyra you're kind of emotional
dojo and and Peter you're the emotional
affective patterns and things like that
this sounds like it's a kind of personal
way of doing trigger practice emotional
trigger practice but I really you know
to speak to some of this method acting
or performative agnostic role or you
know just embodying certain perspectives
I really love the idea cara of having of
setting up a certain social situation
where both people are put into a certain
character and possibly even a character
that has a stance that that you don't
even agree with but are in opposition to
each other and the goal of it is to like
get each other really angry or mad and
just kind of push boundaries but there's
no personal identification to the the
ideology ideological content that's in
the thing but your body doesn't know the
difference I think if specially the more
you get into it
so yeah this kind of relational
emotional affective patterning seems
very rich and yeah I'd be I'd be very
fascinated if you're into exploring that
more I think that'd be really fun so
feel free to reach out to my cell phone
on Twitter or something and anybody else
that I think so
I'm also on the mimetic mediation slack
channel but yeah this was this was fun I
think it was kind of like a we started
out with a very shotgun approach just
kind of like everybody just airing what
they're thinking about and they kind of
felt disjointed but then I kind of
seemed to to pull together at the end
and we found a thread so this was super
fun and and excited to see what happens
next week yeah I agree that was a lot of
good stuff enriched rheya do you want to
briefly talk about your oxytocin party
later flame essentially I'm offering
tonight is a series of embodied
relational experiences to help support
this dance of
the medic tribe and an embodied tribe
and to really like so tonight's gonna be
more fun light-hearted but in hopes to
really create and cultivate this a safe
space to not play it safe so the more
that we can cultivate trust and empathy
and vulnerability within each other the
more that we can continue to grow and
yeah just have this um synergistic
relationship and keep keep keep building
on it so I'm excited it's gonna be a lot
of fun and if you're around I would like
for you to join me mmm I was a little
nervous about it but now I'm like really
excited because I think the nice edge
needs some fun right now so thanks
everyone and I think we'll have another
one next week but I'll confirm with
Jason Jared all right guys take care
thanks everyone